

# Adrián Hinojosa Calleja, PhD

# **Data Scientist**

Barcelona - 611 03 31 20 - hinojosa.a@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/adhinojosa hinojosaad.github.io

A Data Scientist and PhD Mathematics, specializes in Probability. Machine Learning experience with pandas, statsmodel, and sklearn Python's libraries. +10 years teaching mathematics at different educational levels.

# **Educational Background**

### PhD Mathematics

Universitat de Barcelona, 2022 Cum Laude

### **Master Mathematical Sciences**

TU Berlin, Germany, 2016

# **Degree Mathematics**

UNAM, Mexico, 2013
Graduated with honors

# **Certificates**

# **Data Science Bootcamp**

It Academy, 2022

# Introduction to Functional Data Analysis with R

UAB, 2018

# **Technical Skills**

- Python
- R
- SQL
- Power BI
- Java

# **Soft Skills**

- Problem resolution
- Critical thinking
- Teamwork
- Leadership

# **Work Experience**

# **Predoctoral Researcher**

Universitat de Barcelona

April 2017 to January 2022

Researcher in Stochastic Partial Differential Equations.

Teacher's assistant of Probability and Statistics courses.

# **Mathematics Teacher**

Logos Middle School

August 2012 to June 2014

Teacher of Mathematics I and III courses.

# **Organization Experience**

# Organizer

Barcelona's Probability Seminar *January 2021 to March 2022* 

# **Member of the Executive Board**

Institut de Matematiques de la Universitat de Barcelona *November 2017 to January 2022* 

# **Projects**

# Decathlon IT Academy Hackathon, 2022

1st place. Classification model which predicts if a client will buy or not an available product on a webpage.

# Barcelona Air, 2022

Time Series Analysis of pollution concentrations in a neighborhood of Barcelona.

# **Space X, 2022**

3rd Place in the Talent Squad-Data Science Challenge. Classification model to predict the states of turbulence from a space rocket.